{
    "id": "ffd79fa2941941c8b2f57c1491e141eb",
    "title": "General Grammar Quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Would you mind …………………………….. for a minute?",
            "description": "An ing form is used after would you mind.",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "waiting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3dae4f06518e486fa5ef785ff83e8fdc"
        },
        {
            "question": "It isn’t worth …………………………….. to him.",
            "description": "An ing form is used after isn't worth.",
            "answers": [
                "to talk",
                "talking"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0caf78dcbd4c4a22b720682e35b2fad3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why are you talking …………………………… such a loud voice?",
            "description": "We say in a voice.",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "on",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "283cab6f395e48f2b5c949ecf3347f0c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ……………………………… English.",
            "description": "A past tense is used after I wish to express regrets.",
            "answers": [
                "speak",
                "can speak",
                "spoke"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3ee5f9c4ce9c43a7a383dfd3c2bd16ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will be happy when I …………………………….. this project.",
            "description": "A present tense is used in the when-clause when both the main verb and the subordinate verb refers to the future. ",
            "answers": [
                "finish",
                "finished",
                "will finish"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1a7a509fd94c4f88afae51e8a7fa2df8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Winter is ………………………….. the way.",
            "description": "When things are on the way, they are coming.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "86edb8b8cc694f5c9ca65dd9ed3555e7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t stand ………………………….. my way.",
            "description": "When things are in the way, they obstruct movement.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e3c97177b00841cb846808ccc80544ec"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want ……………………………… to him ever again.",
            "description": "A to-infinitive is used after want. ",
            "answers": [
                "talking",
                "to talk"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "80e63c3867dd40a7bb560eec97bc2f59"
        },
        {
            "question": "He drove in a ………………………………. direction.",
            "description": "When these words are adjectives, they do not take -s.",
            "answers": [
                "westward",
                "westwards"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ebca3cad0f1342a6a22c1d996b63b086"
        },
        {
            "question": "We kept going …………………………. until we reached the top.",
            "description": "When these words are adverbs, they can be used with or without -s.",
            "answers": [
                "upward",
                "upwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f7d529e3c4bc4a41a215ce41b5d83333"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will write …………………………….. when I get home.",
            "description": "When write has no direct object, we put to before the indirect object. ",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "to you"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4f55e1664c544ca9815ae6179ba6a6d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Your hair needs ………………………………….",
            "description": "The ing form here means the same as the passive infinitive to be+ past participle. ",
            "answers": [
                "to wash",
                "washing",
                "to be washed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9ede2c54ab7446c8bf7ecd4c153c728f"
        }
    ]
}